## **SVITLANA ZASTER**

### Houston, TX 77057



linkedin.com/in/svitlana-zaster-77a9a06b



https://szaster.github.io/SZPortfolio/



szaster@protonmail.com



(832) 692-2564.

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced full stack coding camp graduate with extensive background in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB developing intuitive web applications from the ground up. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, effective time management. Detail oriented with an analytical mind-set from 10+ years of experience in research, scientific programming and education. Adaptable, diligent, open-minded, creative and flexible. Excellent presentation, communication and organizational skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Wolfram Language, SQL with MySQL and MongoDB

Frameworks: React, Angular, Materialize, Bootstrap, jQuery, Express, Node

Other Tech: GitHub, GitKraken, Sequelize, Mongoose, LaTeX, Wolfram Mathematica

#### **EDUCATION**



The University of Texas at Austin

Mar 2020 - Present

Certificate: Full Stack Development Boot Camp



National Technical University of Ukraine 'Kyiv Polytechnic Institute'

2004

Degree: Master's; Major: Physics, Education



**University of Houston** 

2017

Degree: PhD, Theoretical Physical Chemistry

#### **EXPERIENCE**



#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Mar 2020 - present

#### The University of Texas at Austin

- Wrote complex front end to backend applications with multiple models and data associations, implemented user authentication:
- Designed and developed responsive full stack web applications independently, and in a group setting;
- Mastered CLI and acquired extensive experience in browser-based technologies, server side deployment, databases and quality assurance.



#### **Research Assistant**

2008 - 2017

#### **General Chemistry Instructor**

2008 - 2010, 2020 - present

#### **University of Houston**

- built theoretical models of physical processes and performed scientific programming using Wolfram Language and Wolfram Mathematica;
- published results in peer-reviewed publications;
- demonstrated techniques of the proper and safe laboratory equipment usage

# ĀМ

#### **AWARDS**

Best graduate student poster - Theoretical Chemistry Conference - Texas A&M University

2012

# **SVITLANA ZASTER**